Earth...
土强
Fire...
火烈
本作品采用知识共享署名-相同方式共享 3.0 中国大陆许可协议进行许可。本字幕仅仅供爱好者学习交流
请勿用作商业用途！
Air...
气和
Water.
水善
Only the Avatar can master all four elements
只有神通能掌握所有四种元素
and bring balance to the world.
并为世界带来平衡
降世神通：科拉传奇
After 10,000 years, harmonic convergence is here again,
一万年过去，谐波汇聚再次到来
and the dark spirit Vaatu is free.
黑暗神灵瓦图突破牢狱
Tenzin, Bumi, and Kya
丹增、布米和凯娅
have entered the portal to rescue Jinora's spirit.
进入灵界拯救吉诺拉的魂魄
Asami split from the group and took the injured Tonraq to safety.
麻美离队，把托纳克带到安全地带
So it's up to Korra, Mako, and Bolin to stop Unalaq
所以，只有信、波林和科拉
before he fuses with Vaatu and becomes a dark Avatar.
才能阻止吴纳克和瓦图合体成为逆神通
第二册：神灵篇
第十三集：黑暗降临
Raava, nothing could stop this moment.
拉瓦，什么也挡不了这一刻来临了
Harmonic convergence is upon us again.
谐波汇聚再一次发生在我们面前
I'm not going to let you fuse with Unalaq.
我绝不会让你和吴纳克合体
You're going right back in that prison.
你将继续被封印
Don't let Unalaq back in the spirit world!
不要让吴纳克回到灵界
We're on it!
交给我们了
Jinora.
吉诺拉
Jinora's spirit, do you hear me?
吉诺拉的灵魂哟，你听得到吗
It's your Uncle Bumi.
我是你叔叔布米
Ah, this isn't working.
这样没用
We can't just randomly wander the spirit world, call out for Jinora, and expect to find her!
一边在灵界乱窜一边呼喊吉诺拉，是找不到她的
We just need to employ the simple rules of tracking.
我们只要按追踪的步骤来就行了
First we locate her footprints...
首先我们确定她的脚印的位置
Then we follow them.
然后跟着走
Do you even know what spirit footprints look like?
难道你知道神灵的脚印长什么样？
Do spirits even leave footprints?
神灵能留下脚印吗？
Face it, your tracking skills won't work in the spirit world.
现实点吧，你的追踪能力在灵界是没用的
Let me try something.
我试试这个
Jinora is over there.
吉诺拉在那边
I feel a lot of spiritual energy coming from that direction.
我能感到那边有强大的灵力传过来
We're in the spirit world.
可我们就在灵界里
There's spiritual energy in every direction!
灵力到处都是
Enough!
够了
We can't do this by ourselves.
只靠我们是做不成的
We need a spirit guide.
我们需要灵界引导
There!
看那儿
Spirit, hello.
您好，神灵
I'm sorry to disturb you, but I am in need of your assistance.
很抱歉打扰了您，但我需要您相助
You dare wake me, human?
你竟敢吵醒我，凡人？
Humans in the spirit world
擅闯灵界的凡人
belong in one place only!
只一处归宿
Well, that didn't work.
看来这也不成
Now where are we?
这回我们在哪儿
We're completely lost.
我们彻底迷路了
No!
不！
I don't know if we can win this fight.
不知道我们有没有赢的希望
We don't need to win.
我们不用打赢
We just need to stop Unalaq from getting back in the spirit world.
只要阻止吴纳克回到灵界就行
We're walking in circles!
我们这是在兜圈子
I've seen that same spirit mushroom five times!
那个灵菇我都看见五回了
That's not the same mushroom.
那才不是同一个灵菇
Yes, I am.
我就是
See? Even it knows we're lost.
你看连它都知道我们迷路了
Oh, sure, listen to a fungus over your own brother.
好啊，你宁可信蘑菇也不信你大哥？
What's that?
那是什么？
Mushroom, is that you?
蘑菇，刚刚是你吗？
Nope. Wasn't me.
不，不是我
Iroh? How... Where...
艾洛？怎么…会…
It's been so long.
好久不见
Almost 40 years.
快有四十年了
It's nice to see you again.
很高兴能和你重逢
How did you know we were here?
你怎么知道我们在这里
My friendly spirit fox told me you were lost.
我的朋友狐仙告诉我，你们迷路了
I came to show you the way out.
我来给你们指一指出路吧
Iroh, we are grateful, but we're not looking for the way out...
艾洛，多谢你，但是我们不是要找出路
we're looking for my daughter.
我们在找我的女儿
I'm sorry to hear that, but you shouldn't be here.
真是遗憾，但是你们不应该留在这
Vaatu has escaped, and darkness threatens to take over.
瓦图已经逃走了，黑暗就要降临了
I'm not leaving until I find Jinora.
除非找到吉诺拉，我是不会走的
I understand. But I beg you to be careful.
我能理解，但我恳请你们多加小心
If you travel too deep into the spirit world,
要是你们太深入灵界
you could end up in a place where only the lost will ever find you.
最终到达的地方，恐怕只有迷失者才找得到了
A place where only the lost can find you...
只有迷失者才能找到的地方
That's it!
对了！
I know where to find Jinora!
我知道去哪里找吉诺拉了！
I'm locking you away for another 10,000 years, Vaatu!
我要再把你封印一万年，瓦图
Unalaq?
吴纳克？
Are you out there?
你在不在？
He must have gone home?
他是跑回家了么
Hello, my feeble turtle-duck.
你好啊，我的小龟鸭
Don't let them escape this time.
这回别让他们跑了
Are you sure this is the best way to find Jinora?
你确定这是找到吉诺拉的最好办法？
Trust me.
相信我吧
Hey, you, spirit... wake up!
喂！你，神灵！起来！
You again?
又是你？！
I thought we were going to be taken to a prison.
我还以为我们会被投入大牢里
This is a prison.
可这里和大牢没两样
Welcome to the fog of lost souls.
欢迎光临迷魂雾
You will never escape.
你们再也逃不出去了
Stop!
站住
No!
不好
We are now one.
我们融为一体了
Now a new era for spirits and humans will begin,
如今神灵和凡人的新纪元开始了
and I will lead them all as the new Avatar.
作为新的神通，我会统领他们
Well, I'm the old Avatar, and my era's not over yet.
我是原来的神通，我说我的时代还没有结束
What kind of prison doesn't have any bars or walls?
这算什么大牢，没有铁栅栏也没有高墙
We could walk right out of here.
我们大可以走出去
The fog of lost souls is a spirit prison for humans.
迷魂雾是给凡人魂魄的监牢
I read about it in an ancient text.
我曾经在古书上读到过
The fog is actually a spirit...
这雾，其实是一个神灵
That infects your mind and slowly drives you mad,
它会侵蚀你的心智，慢慢让你发疯
imprisoning you in your own darkest memories.
把你困住，困在最黑暗的记忆里
How long can you be trapped in here?
我们会被困在这里多久？
I am Zhao the Conqueror!
我乃征服者赵
赵（Zhao）：《最后的气宗》第一册水篇第三集首次出现，水篇的主要敌人
水篇第二十集屠月，但最终被海神带走
I am the Moonslayer!
我乃屠月者
I will capture the Avatar!
我一定要抓住神通
I am Zhao the Conqueror!
我乃征服者赵
I am the Moonslayer!
我乃屠月者
I will capture the Avatar!
我一定要抓住神通
Hopefully we're not trapped in here as long as that guy.
但愿我们不会和那边那家伙关一样久
You!
你…
You're him!
就是你
The last airbender!
你是最后的气宗
Ah! No! Get off me!
啊！不！你放手
You've grown... But I will still defeat you!
你长大了，可我一样能战胜你
Come back, Avatar! Face me!
回来啊，神通，跟我较量
I am Zhao the Conqueror! I will capture you!
我乃征服者赵，我一定要抓住你
Victory will be mine!
胜利是属于我的
If we stay together, we'll find Jinora
如果我们在一起，我们就能找到吉诺拉
and make it out of this fog.
然后逃出这团雾
Give in.
放弃吧
Your time is over.
你的时代，结束了
Korra, this fight is not over.
科拉，战斗还没有结束
Raava...
拉瓦…
Vaatu cannot win.
瓦图是赢不了的
Do not give in to 10,000 years of darkness.
不要向万年的黑暗轻言放弃
You are the Avatar.
你，才是降世神通
You cannot win!
你不会赢的！
Jinora!
吉诺拉
Wait a second.
你等一下
What? Do you hear something?
怎么，你听到什么了么
Yes.
是的
They're all around us.
我们被包围了
The cannibals, they're everywhere.
是食人鬼，到处都是
Bumi, you must focus your mind right now.
布米，你现在必须集中精神
There are no cannibals.
周围没有食人鬼
Yes, there are!
明明就有
They're gonna eat every last one of us!
他们会把我们吃得连骨头都不剩的
Who are you two?!
你们俩是谁？
Kya, we're your brothers.
凯娅，我们是你的兄弟
You must remember before the fog infects you.
在雾侵蚀你之前，你一定要想起来
No, you are just a vision. I have no family.
不，你只是个幻觉，我才没有家人
You can't tie me down!
你不能拴着我
They're closing in! I gotta get outta here!
他们要逼近了！我得快逃才行！
- No!
不行！
Bumi! Kya! Come back!
布米！凯娅！快回来！
Please, let us out.
求你们了，放了我们吧
His groveling is pathetic.
他开始求饶了，可怜虫
But I do enjoy the sweet scent of desperation.
不过我还真喜欢听那甜美的绝望的声音
Come on! Your dad has become an evil monster.
拜托，你们的爸爸都变成邪恶的怪物了
He's trying to bring on eternal darkness!
他想要带来永恒的黑暗
Why would you protect someone who doesn't care about you at all?
他根本不在乎你们，你们为什么还保护他
Father was going to let me expire when we tried to open the northern portal...
爸爸在试图打开北极灵界之门的时候确实弃我不顾
Perhaps we should rethink our position.
也许我们是该重新考虑自己的立场了
Yes!
对啊
No. Don't listen to him.
不行，别听他的
His words are poisoning your mind.
他的花言巧语在侵蚀你的头脑
What's with this outburst of emotion?
你干嘛这么激动
I'm sorry, I can't help it.
对不起，可我忍不住了
It's just so sad... that I'll never get to be with you again.
我太伤心了，我再也没法和你在一起了
What?
什么？
Explain yourself further.
你给我再解释清楚点
Eska, I've always loved you, and I've always wanted to be with you...
艾斯卡，我一直都爱着你，一直都想和你在一起
But now that the world is ending, I'm never gonna get that chance.
可是现在世界要完蛋了，我再也没有这机会了
We could have been together, but you left me at the altar.
我们本来能在一起的，可你在祭坛上把我甩下了
No, I was scared!
不，我当时是吓坏了
I was scared of my true feelings for you.
我对你的真正感情，却把我给吓坏了
I should have never left you! I'm sorry.
我真不该把你丢下的，对不起
And I'm sorry that we'll never have a chance to
好可惜我们再也没有机会
rekindle the dying ember that was our love into a...
重新把爱情的余烬点燃成一团
Big fire of love flames.
烈火般的真情了
You'll never defeat my father.
你永远打不赢我父亲的
But should you survive,
不过，如果你活下来
perhaps we can spend eternal darkness together.
也许我们可以一起度过这永恒的黑暗
Wow, that was the best acting I've ever seen.
哇，这是我见过的最棒的演戏
You completely fooled her!
你完全把她唬住了
Yeah, right, that...
唔，好吧
That was acting.
我是演的
They will certainly perish.
他们死定了
I must stay focused.
我得集中精神
Remember who you are, Tenzin.
丹增，要记住自己是谁
You are the son of Avatar Aang.
你是神通安昂的儿子
You are the hope for future generations of airbenders.
你是未来气宗的希望
The fate of the world rests on your shoulders.
这世界的命运就担在你的肩膀上
But what if I fail?
可万一我失败了
Then your father's hope for the future dies with you.
那么你父亲对未来的希望，就和你一同死了
I can't fail!
我不能失败
You will.
你必然失败
Stop it!
住口！
I am the son of Avatar Aang.
我是神通安昂的儿子
I am the hope for future generations of airbenders.
我是未来气宗的希望
I am the son of Avatar Aang!
我是神通安昂的儿子
Hello, my son.
你好，我的儿子
Dad...
父亲…
I've failed you, I am no spiritual leader,
我辜负了您，我没能成为精神领袖
and I've let the world down.
我辜负了这个世界
I'll never be the man you were.
我永远成不了您这样的人
You are right.
你说对了
You are trying to hold on to a false perception of yourself.
你一直都在错误地解读你自己
You are not me, and you should not be me.
你不是我，你也不应该成为我
You are Tenzin.
你，是丹增
I am not a reflection of my father.
我不是我父亲的倒影
I am Tenzin.
我是丹增
我是丹增！
Jinora!
吉诺拉！
What happened?
出什么事了
I think our brother saved us.
看来我们的弟弟救了我们
Dad.
爸
You're going to be okay, sweetie.
你没事了，小乖乖
I'm here.
有我在
What happened?
出什么事了
The last thing I remember is dark spirits taking me away.
我只记得我被恶灵带走了
You were trapped in the fog of lost souls,
你被困在迷魂雾里了
but I wasn't going to let you stay there.
但我不会让你留在里面的
I'm so happy to see you, dad.
爸爸，能见到你，我好高兴
Korra!
科拉！
He's got the light spirit!
他抓住了光明神灵！
The world's in trouble.
世界有麻烦了
What are you talking about? How do you know?
你在说什么，你怎么知道？
I can feel it.
我感觉到了
What happened?
出什么事了
It's Korra.
是科拉
This light spirit will guide you out of the spirit world.
这个光明的灵蝶能带领你们走出灵界
I have to go help.
我必须去帮她
Jinora, wait!
吉诺拉，等等！
Now... 10,000 years of darkness begins!
现在，万年的黑暗时代开始了
本作品采用知识共享署名-相同方式共享 3.0 中国大陆许可协议进行许可。本字幕仅仅供爱好者学习交流
请勿用作商业用途！
降世神通贴吧&Brony United
片源：Ult-Kimi  翻译：TNBi
润色：蓝色的夏天 调轴：TNBi